there can you hear me now there is there
good hi Susie hi thank you so much
gallon your amazing thing I just had to
say that and then I'll leave this got so
and hi John how are you
happy to do it anything for Julian are
you wearing John are you wearing a red
striped shirt I am and I am wearing a
red stripe shirt it was either that or
the John Lennon shirt but I think I wore
that last time I'm not knocking it I
could see the very top of the shirt and
I know my Jamaican beers but maybe not
that well but I just don't laugh I ask
for that's great how you doing I'm okay
thanks
you can tell behind me I just moved into
a new house day before yesterday so it's
chaos so I apologize in advance I don't
have a I don't have a professional
background like you do yours looks good
you got the antique there's a wall so
wait by the way I don't want to startle
you but there's someone behind you I
don't want I thought I don't I don't
want to scare you
hey how's it going nice to see you good
I just I'm glad you know John's John's
ex-cia
you know I should warn him so uh so
let's let's talk about that John so I
get to interview you which is exciting
but people should know that you and I
know each other because we both host
co-host shows and radio Sputnik I host
fault lines of Nixon Stranahan with
Garland Acheson was just on you co-hosts
loud and clear with Brian Becker and you
and I also I'll say this John I like you
I like you I always yeah so I think John
and I is it fair to say we're we're
friends I think we're friends
you know work friends yes we don't go
fishing together
not yet but no yeah I don't fish I'm not
angleton and I'm single again so I I
have plenty of time to fish now really
okay good
good yeah well do the happy hours but
but so it's been fascinating for me
getting to know you over the past few
months because I do generally first off
I you know I like you as a guy and
I always like talking to you but it's
it's rare to be able to talk to somebody
who is a ex-cia right that's unusual
right and who also took a stand when you
took your stand against let's so just
briefly briefly give that little bit of
your bio for people who might not know
it because I think it it's neat but
people don't you're an ex-cia officer
head of counterterrorism in Pakistan in
2002 among other things and then what
happened just tell that story real
briefly you know it started I usually
say it started in 2007 it actually
didn't start in 2007 it started in 2002
after the capture of Abu Zubaydah who we
believed at the time was the number
three in al-qaeda we caught up as a beta
at the end of March 2002 and then I
returned to CIA headquarters in May of
2002 I only been home a couple of days
and a senior officer asked me if I
wanted to be his words trained in the
use of enhanced interrogation techniques
I had never heard the term before again
mid 2002 he explained to me what it was
I said that's a torture program you can
use whatever euphemism you want it's a
torture program I don't want any part of
it I didn't realize at the time that I
became known as the human rights guy at
the CIA which is not career enhancing
but I took it very seriously you know I
I took my oath to the Constitution
seriously I took respect for
international law and human rights very
seriously
and so I was the only person out of
fourteen who were approached who
declined to be trained in the torture
program I resigned from the CIA two
years later went into the private sector
I kept waiting for somebody to come
forward to essentially blow the whistle
on the torture program which I believed
then and I believe now was both illegal
and immoral well and unethical as well
so nobody came forward and I waited
three more years three and a half more
years and finally in December of 2007 I
went on ABC News
and I said that the CIA was torturing
its prisoners I said the torture was
official US government policy and I said
that the policy had been personally
approved by the president
so as you might imagine the CIA referred
me to the FBI as having committed a
grave national security crime the FBI
investigated me from December of 2007 to
December of 2008 and then determined
that I had not committed a crime and
closed the case
a month later Barack Obama becomes
president and brings John Brennan on
board as the deputy national security
adviser John and I go way back into the
late 80s we have not liked each other
since the late 80s and John secretly
asked the Justice Department to reopen
the case against me I had no idea that I
was under investigation again and so for
the next three years until January of
2012 the FBI tapped my phones they
intercepted my emails they had periodic
teams of physical surveillance following
me and then in January of 2012 I was
charged with five felonies coming out of
that ABC News interview including three
counts of espionage of course I hadn't
committed espionage and the charges were
eventually dropped but not until I I
took a plea to a lesser charge I was
already over a million dollars in debt
to my lawyers and so to make the thing
go away I took a plea to a lesser charge
I did 23 months in a federal prison
never apologizing because I still
believed in my heart I did nothing wrong
it's the government that did the wrong
and got out in February of 2015 and sort
of took my place among those of us who
are now activists for human rights and
civil liberties and and civil rights and
activists against government overreach
and for government transparency and
WikiLeaks falls squarely in that
category well and so so well
I think one of the reasons I wanted you
to tell that story actually is because
for for me and almost everybody else
doing this unity thing the Julian
Assange situation is obviously
disturbing awful but it's academic in
the sense that you spent I'm gonna say
this again 23 months in prison yeah and
how many people who are doing I'm just
saying there's nothing I'm not knocking
anybody I'm knocking me too
I've never spent six months in prison
much less 23 so what I'm saying is for
you I'm very curious for you with your
experience
this shit's real with Julian right I
mean well how does I mean does how does
your prison experience affect how you
view knowing what that experience dude
you see the question I'm asking bout
adout and and that's when I say when I
tell people I know from firsthand
experience what Julian is going through
I mean that I literally know yes
first-hand experience what Julian's
going through because you know people
could say Oh Julian's in an embassy and
he has access to television and he has
whatever he used to have internet and
visitors Julian's in solitary
confinement I mean the UN has even said
that Julian's in solitary confinement if
you are in a position where you you
literally do not even have access to
sunlight that is solitary confinement
there are prisoners in in maximum
security u.s. Penitentiary's who have
more day-to-day freedoms than Julian
Assange does and that's what people have
to understand that it's not that that
he's living the good life he's living
high off the hog in some plush foreign
embassy that's just not the case I mean
if you don't have access to sunlight if
you don't have access to to exercise
it's gonna take a toll on your health
and it's gonna shorten your life and
that's exactly the same kind of thing
that we see in solitary confinement in
prisons across the United State
well and you you also you know you you
you raised a very interesting point
peripherally when you said you you've
been cleared Obama gets in office and
then not Obama says hey John Brennan
let's look into this Kuryakin guy but
Brennan I'm trying to show who driving
who's driving the bus okay that's a
great question too if I could interrupt
you for one second young and by no
stretch of the imagination of fan or
supporter of Donald Trump but I will
tell you that John Brennan who has been
harassing Donald Trump since the man
became president was the person who
targeted me for the reopening of the
investigation I can tell you that Robert
Muller the special counsel who has been
investigating Donald Trump and those
around him for the last whatever it is
18 months set up the John Kiriakou task
force when he was head of the FBI and
that's what it was called the John
Kuryakin task force so I know what Trump
is going through there and it was Peter
stroke the FBI agent who arrested me on
January the 12th 2012 so I know exactly
what Donald Trump at all are going
through and you know it seems to me that
in part that's one of the reasons why we
have heard Trump more than once joke or
maybe not joke about Julian Assange and
WikiLeaks and it's because they actually
have something in common we all do right
we all know what government overreach is
we all know what happens when you are
targeted by someone targeted by a
government that has unlimited resources
unlimited manpower and dedicates itself
not just to ruining you
I mean ruining is easy but dedicates
itself to making sure that you die in
prison and that's what their goal is
with Julian Assange and why why is that
their goalie because it's Julian that
has been exposing the crimes committed
by governments and other sovereign
entities around the world well so okay
so let me let me try a theory out on you
I'm going to
the theory and view as a four CIA
officer student of CIA history let me
try this on you one of the things I'm
trying to do when I think about what
American propaganda looks like that
people believe if I had to say what's
the one of the big lies is we're taught
from childhood in school that our
government has three branches the
executive the legislative and the
judicial branch right that's a lie it's
a lie
I would argue that in fact since about
World War two with the funding you know
when after the CIA was set up in 47 goes
into operation 48 right interfering the
Italian election just saying that since
then effectively Truman tried to warn us
Eisenhower tried to warn us that in fact
we have an unelected fourth branch of
government you can call it the deep
state or the military-industrial complex
you can call it the some of the
intelligence community the CIA doing not
just advising the president which was
their original purpose but doing
operations and that in fact if you think
the government is actually three
branches with checks and balances you're
not you're just wrong it's this fourth
branch that actually runs things what I
mean by that is not that there's not
some wiggle room because if they
completely ran things it would be chaos
but I mean it would be it would be much
more of a police state than it is now so
these other branches still sort of act a
little as a check and balance on them
but that broadly speaking I feel I
forget whether you like Donald Trump I
hate and we have the alike Obama or hate
him they're not as in charge as everyone
would like to pretend that they are and
so what do you think of this this theory
that one of the big lies is just the
weak we don't live in that system that
we're taught in civics class in third
grade at all I wouldn't even call that a
theory I would call that fact right yeah
that's fact when you've got when you've
got three consecutive presidents in
Harry Truman Dwight Eisenhower and
John Kennedy who all warned us about the
military industrial complex who warned
us about the CIA and about unelected
bureaucrats running government we should
have taken heed and we didn't and now
especially since the 9/11 attacks it's
too late
at least it's too late without some sort
of a counterbalance which I believe
WikiLeaks is or at least should be
because you've got these unelected
officials who know that they can
outweigh any president look the CIA
hated Jimmy Carter but they knew that
because presidents come and go that they
can wait out Jimmy Carter and they did
they weren't crazy about Bill Clinton
either and Clinton finally left
they hate Donald Trump but they know
Donald Trump's gonna go one of these
days and they're still gonna be there
we're talking about people at the CIA
the FBI NSA dia and these other
three-letter agencies who are there for
20 25 30 in some cases 40 years these
guys are entrenched in these
intelligence service bureaucracies while
presidents come and go and these guys
know that they really run the day-to-day
operations of the government so when
Donald Trump says God bless WikiLeaks on
the campaign trail these guys at the CIA
and the FBI they chuckle to themselves
because it doesn't matter what Donald
Trump thinks about WikiLeaks it only
matters what they think about WikiLeaks
because they know that once these
presidents go they're still going to be
there and I will say the one thing that
that that whoever's presidents got going
for them is that they have the bully
pulpit in a way that no other American
has there's not a senator on the hill
who if they do a press conference
guaranteed every cameras going to show
up does that make sense even Grassley
had it had it right McConnell head of
the Senate they might not cover it
Donald Trump walks into the White House
press room every camera in the world is
gonna be on him and whoever's president
every camera in the world and that's
that bully pulpit and that's why and I
think the thing they're so scared of
with Trump is if he
figures out that he's not really in
charge they're doing a good job
Pompeyo former you know was Pompeo knows
how to play him see here's the thing as
a CIA guy you know how to play people
how hard is Donald Trump to figure out
for you that what how does Donald Trump
know of course how does Donald Trump
react when you criticize him publicly
and the way you control Donald Trump is
you it helped inflate his ego pump him
up and then you get what you want
and that's exactly what Mike Pompeo has
done my my yeah Mike Pompeo was a nobody
Mike Pompeo was a three-term congressman
from Kansas he was a member of the
Intelligence Committee big deal and next
thing you know he's the director of the
CIA and the next thing you know after
that he's the Secretary of State the
guys in overhead now he's a smart guy
he's West Point grad he graduated from
Harvard Law is a very smart smart guy
but more important than being smart is
he knows how to play Donald Trump and so
where we've seen this this personnel
bloodbath elsewhere in the
administration
Pompeyo has proven to be a survivor
because he knows exactly how this game
is played as has a Bolton yes came in
and as said people like Stephen Miller
for instance whoo-hoo-hoo I know Steve
Miller from before when he's an
administration something that was a guy
like banning couldn't hang he couldn't
hang because he didn't know at the end
of the day he's just gotta think I think
he just got sick of he's used to being
CEO so I just think he got sick of
playing that role with Trump but this is
why they're so dangerous and again I try
to say this to people because what
happens is people's political biases
they go
I hate Trump and I hate him because and
there's a lot of valid reasons to hate
Trump as I think there are valid reasons
to hate almost any politician I can
think of now but what I what I try to
explain to people is given the choice
between Hillary Clinton and Donald Trump
hands down
Donald Trump if you're trying to smash
this
state apparatus was the bet was the
better choice in that election at least
there was the apparatus right yes I mean
whether you like politics or dislike her
politics Hillary Clinton was the deep
state I mean she was a part of she's
been around forever she said your job
every important important job in foreign
policy she was on the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee when she was on
Capitol Hill Secretary of State she was
first lady and had foreign policy duties
as first lady so yeah she's part of this
this state that we're rallying against
that's that's right and and she's also
the one who called for Julian Assange to
be what drone ders I would say with
every eight the exact phrase but yeah
but she told her to be drone so so her
she's she would have been wet I'll put
like this she would have been worse in
an ideal world we would have had Sanders
let's say versus Trump and that would
have been better and a lot of people
wanted that but again Hillary kept that
from happening in WikiLeaks exposed it
and that's why I think that it's very
interesting to me that people who were
perceived and actual enemies of the DNC
who know things Paul Manafort whether
you approve of his lobbying activities
which I don't actually I think I don't
like lobbying but but that being said he
was the only guy for instance in the
Trump our meeting who knew what was
going on you can tell that from his
notes immediately when they arrested man
afford they put a gag order on him
because he's one of the few people who
actually understands what's going on and
could say you know I wasn't actually
supporting Russia with the Party of
Regions I was suggesting they go with
the EU which they in his trial they had
to admit the government had to admit
that he was actually telling Yanukovych
to go away from Russia but with with
Manta Ford and Julian Assange
not many people compare those two but I
think part of putting both of them
behind bars was just to shut them up and
about the same things actually
because the stock mana for nose would
have demolished this Russia gate
narrative and the stuff Assange knows
crushes the Russia gate in air if he
literally knows where they who gave him
the material and he said it's not
non-state actor let me add something to
that Trump knows that and I Trump asked
Bill Binney who's a friend of ours to go
to the Oval Office six or eight months
ago and to explain to him the science
behind the DNC information release I
don't want to call it a hack because it
was but the DNC information release and
Bill Binney was able to explain and I'm
gonna say this as a layman because
that's all I am and I don't understand
the science of it either but Bill beany
explained that the information that came
from the DNC judging by the speed of the
upload could only have been an upload to
a thumb drive it could not have been
done remotely which confirms what julian
has been saying all along that the
information that came from the DNC those
DNC emails were the result of a
whistleblower not the result of a remote
hack and true so so by the way I will
just tell you and I we I've had Benny on
the show too i person i will say this
and move on I personally disagree with
that theory based on the search that
I've done but it's a complex technical
matter but the fact that Trump was open
to Benny being there and then got
trashed by Pompeo the other story I will
tell you about that I'd like your
feedback on I don't think we've actually
talked about this is that in Woodward's
new book something very interesting
comes out i've been covering this
ukraine DNC story for a long time and
I've been talking to a guy named Andre
tell chenko he was the whistleblower who
worked
he's anti-russian he's Ukrainian he was
part of the Madonn and he was the guy
who worked at the Embassy and we become
friends now and he knows I worked for
Sputnik and he's like thrilled with that
but okay right he's an honest guy he's a
whistleblower
mcmaster it comes out in Woodward's new
book told trump that the idea that there
was DN c-- ukrainian collusion was
russian propaganda and andres one who
told me about it because they've never
interviewed him nobody's ever
interviewed him they know who he is he
sent letters to them he said I will
testify under oath about exactly what
happened furthermore what he's going to
testify to has already been affirmed by
Alexander chalupa the DNC operative who
was was she in Politico in January 2017
Ken Vogel and David Stern wrote an
article she admits it all to them write
and tell the Cinque O's in that article
so think about this McMaster without any
and Woodward says parts of the IC as
well had all said oh that DNC Ukraine
thing Russian propaganda and they never
talked never even tried to talk telly
chenko he comes to the he was at
McCain's funeral he was invited let me
put this this is a guy who was invited
to John McCain's funeral so that tells
you who this guy is he's not a Russian
bot right and and but but he's an honest
guy who when they said to him don't
coordinate with Trump and we're good we
want you to dig up dirt for the DNC
which is what he was told and I've
interviewed him about this he just said
I'm not gonna do this cuz it's gonna
work it could backfire what if she
doesn't win and he's a loyal Ukrainian
it was like this isn't gonna work out
well but I I think it's a clear example
to me that the people around Trump like
McMaster are feeding him lies that they
didn't even try to investigate so from
your experience is there anything like
illegal about I know you're not a lawyer
but like like it aren't you supposed to
investigate like so much say it was
illegal as much as I would say it's
institutionalized incompetence you know
you've got these guys like McMaster who
are a part of the problem they're a part
of the deep state I mean masters been in
the military for what thirty years
thirty two years
didn't get those three or four shiny
stars on his shoulder by by being the
outlier and and making trouble for
people he knows exactly what he's doing
and this is kind of this is kind of a
mistake that Trump has made where he has
surrounded himself with people who you
and I would consider to be
representative of the deep state now I
understand that really because this is a
new president he's never been in
politics before he's never held elective
office before and he needs some insiders
advising him just so he knows what's
going on on a day-to-day basis with that
said you know he turned to the people
who I think could cause him the most
harm the likes of McMaster and and John
Kelly and and Jim mattis and all these
other people who have made made a life
for themselves in the
military-industrial complex
yeah and and appointed me because I try
you know again I worked for Steve a
netbright but I tried to tell Bannen
about this when he was in the White
House and say look let me explain this
Ukraine story to you probably didn't
want to hear it but he didn't want to
hear it but but but I honestly don't
maybe I'm naive see I'm not like people
have lots of motivations I don't think
was like political I think was just more
he's arrogant you know and it didn't
it's and just whatever he didn't want to
hear it but hey I guess I'm seeing I
think it's time to move on right okay so
wait hang on one second I'm just reading
the chat window forgive me everybody I'm
very bad eyesight but but yeah I mean I
just you know I let's let's let's finish
is this because we're waiting for Joe
Laurie the great jewelery to come on by
the way once again I mean Joe from
consortium news helped organize these
things done an amazing job and also I
think both you and I appreciate the work
Susie and everybody else has done
putting this together yeah me too no no
John what do you think the best thing
people could do going forward to
more light to this issue is thinking
strategically with the state of play as
it is right now do you have any ideas on
effective activism that you think would
work or maybe it's effective working
through the legislature or something
what do you think would work well there
are a couple of things you know I've
learned a lot of lessons since this this
whole thing started one of those lessons
is that activism works if you're patient
with it and I'll give you an example
I've got a group of friends in North
Carolina they're all retirees they're
all senior citizens and and they
discovered that their local airport was
the staging ground for CIA rendition
flights around the world it's just a
little tiny Municipal Airport in rural
North Carolina and so they went to the
owner of this Airport I told the story
in this in this venue before but I'm
gonna repeat it they went to the owner
of the airport and they said listen we
know that that the CIA is staging its
rendition flights here we want you to
cancel that contract he told him to get
the heck off this property so then they
started protesting in front of the
entrance the airport carrying signs and
banners and marching back and forth
people ignored them then they started
laying down in the in the highway and
blocking traffic and they made
themselves such pains and this guy's ass
that he canceled his contract with the
CIA now the CIA likely just moved on to
another airport but I mean if we all do
that if we all work toward that end if
we all maintain our activism our
excitement over activism we can really
get things done one of the things that's
really important to me in the last few
days Lee in this in this fight against
Brett Kavanaugh the likes of of code
pink and any number of groups that have
opposed the Kavanagh nomination is that
even when it became clear to them that
Cavanaugh was going to win this vote and
and assume a seat on the Supreme Court
they kept up their activism and it made
the news the mainstream news and when
that happens you reach more people and
you influence more people now you and I
talked about this these issues on our
own shows I
about this all the time for either
consortium news or for reader supported
news sometimes for truth din ik a couple
of times for The Washington Post in the
Los Angeles Times but we all have to
keep this up we all have to be be public
and forceful with our activism because
over a period of time we really do
convince people that we're right and you
know now now it's crunch time
if we're to believe if we're to believe
what former president correa has been
saying the last couple of days that
Julian's in trouble we need to stand up
to protect him and we need to do
literally everything that that's in our
power to protect him not to think about
it and ponder the issue and you know
post something on Facebook I'm with
Julian we need to be out there marching
shutting down Senate offices maybe
getting arrested writing publishing
speaking talking on radio and television
programs we need to do everything that
we can to make sure that the country
understands what our position is on this
and that we're with Julian that's really
what it comes down to you know one of
the things I'll just throw out there
since one of the things that these unity
4je things end up being almost in a
weird way especially since Susie's on
and listening is it's like a big meeting
of the minds of okay so what do we do
about this you know what I mean and one
of the things I will say I'll just throw
this out there I think one of the things
that's needed and it's very easy to
forget this the absolute basics for
people who sort of kind of know who
Julian Assange is and there's a lot of
people in that category my wife who is
not hugely political but certainly
follows me she was like okay so what's
going on he's in where is he again and
she's not dumb and she's not she's
people she's my wife is most people most
people have sort of heard the name
Julian Assange and right now if I were
to say to somebody let's go where's the
basics where's just the okay
was put in here this time here's what
the you know like the basics in a nice
graphic way or something like that that
makes it easy step 1 step 2 step 3 oh I
get it now why is he in the embassy
because it's a weird thing if you think
about it Bob my wife's because it's like
so wait a minute is he in prison or Z
because I hear about an embassy it's
easy for us to forget that most people
don't know that it's easy for everybody
on these calls to forget that most
people probably don't even know Julian
Assange right if you took a poll
probably 51% don't know they you know
who is that an actor I don't know is
that the guy who played Sherlock Holmes
or whatever and and and so I'm just
gonna throw that out there I think one
form of activism is also not because the
kind of activism everyone's talking
about is great and needed but it's also
preaching to the choir does that make
sense we've got to get to the mainstream
media you're right it's I mean these
events are great and I really enjoy them
and I actually reward them but but we're
all in agreement here and this is
speaking to the choir we need to get to
the people who disagree with us or more
importantly as you're pointing out right
now to the people who really don't know
what's going on yeah that's it's a
winning issue one up a bottle like this
once people understand it they'll go
yeah that's messed up right but it's a
matter of getting people there and also
as anyone who understands political or
you know here's another thing I'll just
throw this out - it's interesting
I see Joe so I don't I don't want to
keep Joe but this is absolutely
fascinating conversation for me to
listen to about how we can evolve this
into a greater and bigger movement in
terms of anti-war efforts also what John
was just saying is something that I've
been really concerned about which is
that we just speak to the same audience
and I think that the unity platform
allows us to speak to a different
audience and allows us to draw in
different audiences because I know
certainly you know in Berlin I had
intestines
billon I learned a ton working with the
world's best privacy activists for
nearly a year but of the European
conference circuit is very much like a
year-long holiday that everybody just
hops from event to event to event year
in year out and I don't know that we
were actually pushing into that new
territory or enlarging the audience and
I certainly hope that with this I just
want to say something to you guys really
quickly because Joe made reference
earlier to their having been some
attacks on unity as a concept of course
that was always going to happen I
predicted that right from the outset of
movement as standard for any movement
what was a little bit different with
this as nobody fell for it so and from
what they know movement so we have 70 I
think now 80 for all participants
we had about 70 participants at the
point last month where an organization
well it just actually seems to be one
random guy but whatever started writing
nasty blog post about us started taking
the links to those blog posts and
emailing them to all our participants
and to asking them to make public
statements against us in to decry our
platform to undermine a platform then
taking all our movement supported them
anyone who tweet on a hashtag I'm on
Twitter message it private this you can
look on Facebook just totally
coordinated comprehensive smear campaign
against unity and I just want to say
that two days not one single one of our
participants has withdrawn or their
support or written a statement against
movement or anything like that and this
is not sick that one day that might not
ever happen I'm pretty amazed to see
that even with that type of social
pressure even with those type of tactics
being used and especially words like
racist fascist white supremacists are
being invoked even though they
completely unfounded but they really
highly charged words the words that come
with significant peer and stigma and
still everybody has has held strong and
the other thing like this and so it
seems like this can go the course and
for every one person who has detracted
from this movement from the public
sphere there has
easily been 100 easily 100 to 1 saying
this is necessary
we need this we've been waiting for this
it's like once you give people the
license to interact with each other
again they grab onto it and don't want
to let it go is this the key is what I'm
really asking to overcome not you know
to overcome the divide and conquer I
feel like when we go to school we go to
school with people who believe all
different things when we go and get a
job we have to work with people who
believe different things we can't be
like oh you know if you're not a liberal
you're not a conservative then and I'm
not going to work with you it's trucking
company or wherever you work um why is
it in the active business fear that
we've been so siloed and can we less
this public over the first it looks like
an experiment of finally overcoming the
divide can we push that out wider into
the into the public so who you are
anybody and everyone carry a John's just
paying his moving guy I'll be back in a
minute
what are your thoughts well so one of
the things is interesting about the
American political scene I'll just use
that is that we have the Democrats the
Republicans the Democrats have a
dysfunctional election system in other
words clearly WikiLeaks exposed
corruption that helped Hillary Clinton
win right but they've got a very
functional activism system and you could
see that with the Cavanaugh hearings
where the activism end of it on the
other hand the Republicans have a
completely broken activism system they
suck at activism but at least candidates
can make it through the gauntlet in a
way they can't on the DNC side and I
think this works to the deep states
advantage by the way that that both
these systems are broken in different
ways but I think what's interesting
about the unity Forge a movement is
people on the Left clearly understand
organizing and activism on a great on
out on in a way because there's constant
training and stuff like that that people
who are more on the right I've been on
both have been on the left and the right
and so I know a little bit more than
most
all right but I think the thing is if
you look at the people who are
participating in unity for J you have so
much institutional knowledge and the
strength of it is from a diverse range
of people and ideas from a John Kiriakou
with CIA experience who can take that
training and go well you know I think
here's how the CIA does propaganda maybe
we should use that to people like Joe
Lauria with you know mainstream media
experience yeah Roger I was gonna say a
great deal you see what you see what I'm
getting at is think of the huge
diversity of people that we have that
can really be a strength here I think
but if we find a way to harness it so
that's that's my thought on that God you
know we need we need a steering
committee we need it we need a steering
committee because right now what we have
is a massive amount of human resource
we're calling them the wiki bees and
three days a week we all get together
and we do these live streams of us
actually working to progress the
movement and it's like literally soccer
moms and grandparents and you know even
like teenagers and people with you know
three jobs are still taking couple hours
to do it but we need to it's a very
task-oriented it's very technical
what we need is a steering committee
that can provide strategies and like
meet once a month and get our view for
this is what we want to achieve this
month so that I can take that back to
the wiki base and be like okay his
iTaste breakdown will go to achieve
let's go and I'll say I love the idea
we're kind of doing this with these
unity 4j interviews but maybe it could
be more formalized I love the idea that
of course the problem nobody likes
committees because everybody's been on
them and they know how it goes but if
you could do a the planning community
ring committee and make it transparent
and open and public that's a very
wikileaks approach right - and it would
alleviate some of the problems which is
I'm pissed at John because he put took
my parking space and then that Devon you
know lots of these committee meetings
behind closed doors everybody knows it
gets into the stupidest bullsh
in the world and it derails
whatever activism people are doing
because all this you can't do that
publicly because everybody in the
audience is gonna go wait even can you
guys just take this outside let's talk
about the Julian issue cuz that's all we
should be so I don't know I'm just gonna
throw that out there but anyway look I
appreciate again now Joanne and Susan
you're on John and I both said it thanks
so much for the work you guys are doing
thanks so much for the tireless work
you're doing and and and thanks for for
a my and allowing me to be part of this
thank you you know I'm just gonna say
these people who were targeted for
smears for month in this campaign are
people who have given me zero drama zero
and cause for concern who have never
created any problem for us and who have
given freely of their time and been a
hundred percent committed to Julian in
toluca leagues and that data I put more
credibility and stock in that than I
ever will and what someone else some
random person says about them
so it's just want to point that out you
have been tireless in your support
okay I'm gonna bow out as well because
here we have one of the most brilliant
minds and gentlemen the most experienced
minds and journalism Joe Lauria and we
have one of the world's foremost
whistleblowers and I would love to say
this they're being close with a
conversation between you two and I will
have a think on the steering committee
stuff when we might see what we can put
together over the next month though
thank you guys thank you John so much
and thank you Joe okay